Welcome to this video. In this video, we
will see how do we create a agent that
supports multi-turn conversation. It
means that for instance first user will
be asking hey like what is the weather
in Toronto and like the second question
he will be asking what are all the
places that I can visit right so for the
second question the user is not saying
like which city he is looking at rather
like he is saying like hey what are all
the places that I can refer right so in
that sense like agent should know the
user is actually talking about the city
Toronto which he mentioned in the first
question Right? In that sense, the agent
should keep the conversation, right? So,
it should be able to refer back to the
previous history, conversation history
and uh you know, extract the relevant
information, right? So, in order to do
that, we have something called a thread.
So, that's what we will be discussing,
right? In this particular, it's pretty
simple. If I just come over here like uh
actually like I just create a agent you
know similar to like how we used to
create the agent and like when you have
a agent all you need to do is that you
need to create something called a
thread. So when you create a thread and
use the thread when you submit you know
your input to the agent the agent will
make use of this particular thread and
capture all the relevant information
going forward as long as you provide
this thread information in the
subsequent conversation right so
basically like uh behind the scenes
Microsoft takes care of you know
capturing all this information putting
it under the uh thread right you really
don't have to do anything that is the
beauty of this framework work right all
you need to do is that again just create
a thread pause it with your conversation
right so now let's go ahead and see like
how exactly it works so again like if at
all you wanted to delete the thread you
can very well delete the thread so where
do I see the thread right so if if I
just come over to the portal here if you
just come over click on this agent and
if you just go here it will create a
thread for us whenever you say hey like
create a new thread something of this
sort get a new thread it will create a
thread for for you. So what happens like
if you don't specify this thread
information like so for the agent will
still create a thread but that is
something called a disposable thread. So
once the execution it's done the thread
will be disposed it is of no use right
but like when you create a thread the
history will be stored. So now let's go
to the visual studio and see like how
exactly it works here. It's all going to
be the same but then like um as said I'm
just creating a new thread here and um
the user questions are like what is the
weather in Tokyo and I pass the thread
information they was again asking what
was the last city he asked about right
so now again like he is asking like how
compared to London's weather right
because like we are using a weather tool
here for all these we will be just
responding back the static content here
like the weather in that particular city
it's a sunny or whatever is the time be
London beat Tokyo or whatever is that so
that is what we will be responding back
because like that is the tool that we
are referring here right so now uh let's
see like how exactly this works right
now let me go ahead and run the program
so this is going to give me 16 program
thread so let it run in between like if
you see here like this is this is how
this will get executed right so first we
create a thread so now we will pass that
user query along with the thread
information. Now what Azure service will
do is that in case of any history exist
in the history database, it will pull up
that information, pass it to the LLM,
the agent will respond back and like
finally it will save that information
into the thread history. So in the
upcoming uh user query if you say hey
like what is the city that I asked? So
now again like the user like we we are
passing this thread information it will
again go back and pull up the history
from the database and pass it to the
llm. So that way like the overall
conversation it's stored somewhere. So
the agent can always refer back you know
because if I expand this one so first
like what is the weather like in Tokyo
the weather in Tokyo it's a sunny
whatever is that what is the last city
that I asked about the city that it's
Tokyo because now again like it respond
back the weather in London it's also
sunny with the same degree because like
we are using the tool that always
returns the same weather information. Uh
so it says that the whether in both
tokun it's the same it it all happens
because of this thread and the history
it's being you know perceived in the uh
thread database right we don't we really
don't have to do anything you know in
order to manage all this conversation I
remember like in the past we have to you
know send the user queries back and
forth the overall payload will will be
so huge now thanks to thread we really
don't have to do anything just pass this
thread information right so now let me
clear this console so let's see like how
do we make use of a existing thread
right so in the previous program like I
showed you like what is this thread how
do we use that right now in this program
what I want to do is that I really you
know quickly want to create a API and
like user will be using that particular
API to interact with the agent and like
he will be passing the thread
information back and forth Right now
overall execution it is going to be the
same. So I have the same kind of a
weather tool here. Right. And like what
I do is that I created a fast API client
here and this is what will host my
agent. Right? Now what I want to do is
that uh this program. So what I want to
do here is that
uh when a user
has a hosting he will be passing the
thread information. If there is no
thread information it's given then it
will create a new thread uh and like
when it return back it will always
return back two two things like adds to
the user query as well as the thread
information. So what user have to do is
that in the next time he will be
reaching this API he will be passing the
next query plus the thread information
right basically like the thread ID he
needs to pass that. So that's how we can
use it. Now with that like let me go
ahead and run this program. So python
17.
Okay let me run that. So quickly it will
create a fast API.
Now let me go and uh run this uh curl
commands here.
So let me copy this. So what I'm saying
is that this is running in the port
8,000. So with the with the endpoint
chat I'm asking you what is the weather
like in London. Same query right? But
this time around the thread ID because
like this is my first conversation. I
really don't have the thread ID and run
call and that is going to hit the API.
So it is going to create agent and then
like it is going to respond back. Now I
have the thread ID here. Now if you see
the weather in London, it's sunny with
whatever the weather is that right now I
copy this thread ID and I will pass this
information right to the subsequent
query. So I will go and run this curl
command.
So now as we are passing the thread
information it should have access to the
previous query rain. So now it sees the
weather in Paris also sunny whether
whatever is that. So it sees here also
sunny because like it knows that we have
breakfast or the information
for a specific city. Right now if you
wanted to you know go ahead and do the
multi- turn conversation you can very
well do that by pausing this sread
information between your calls. Now
let's go ahead and discuss about the
next topic that is going to be a state
management. So you have noticed
um the chargation
you will have all your previous
conversation listed right when you click
on that it will load all this
information. So how exactly it does? So
behind the scenes it stores the thread
ID and its relevant information. So
think of this way. So for each
conversation there is going to be a
thread created and like when you have a
multiple conversation each conversation
will have a thread information. So
somehow you should be able to capture
and store this thread information. when
a user opens your charge GPT UI you
should be able to pull all the thread
information related to a specific user
and based on which you have to you know
build all this right so in order to do
that you can very well use the state
management so basic when you have your
thread information you can serialize and
deserialize this thread information
that's what we are going to discuss in
this particular topic right so first we
will have a thread history dojson so in
which we will be capturing all the
thread relevant information. If a file
exist, we will des serialize. If doesn't
exist, we will create one, right? And
like in this particular file, we will be
storing all the thread information,
right? So, and like when a user runs,
then um you know it will des serialize
and see like if there are any existing
uh thread then it will load that thread
into the in you know user request and
then like it will it will respond back
to us. Right? So now let me go ahead and
run this particular program. Let me
clear the console here again. So if you
see here it will create a file something
called you know something like this. So
thread history.json. So in which it will
store all this relevant information. So
let me first go and delete this file. So
before I run that. So now let me go
ahead and run this particular file 18.
Now let me go ahead and run this file.
So now it is asking us um what is your
input. So first let me ask what is the
capital of India. So it is again going
to create a agent and like agent will
respond back. Now the thread history
dojson file get created. If you see here
like number of messages one and this is
the thread id right. So basically like
the whenever you create a thread uh the
agent framework provides a mechanism for
you to serialize and deserialize and
store this information. So basically
storing it's up to you but then like a
serializing and deserializing it's part
of a Asian framework right and then like
now let me go ahead and ask this what is
the capital of Canada so now it is again
going to you know now it has the user
input and like it will load the profile
information profile history and it will
respond back to us. So it says the
capital city of Canada it's Atava and
like how far they are because now I am
not saying like which city we are
talking about right because I already
mentioned two cities and that
information it's part of a thread and
the program has access to the thread it
should be able to pull up this
information now if you go here let let
it complete so it says that um the
distance between New Delhi and datawites
whatever the distance is the train it it
has some information for us now if you
Just go here. It says that hey like this
is the thread you are you know using it
and the like you have. So you can very
well you know have this thread
information somewhere like in a JSON
file or in your database. So typically
you will be storing this information in
a database right? So that like you can
whenever a user access your UI then you
can pull up all the information and show
it to the user. when a user click on
that particular topic you know
particular user input or whatever is
that then at the time you know like what
thread he is talking about or you know
relevant to that particular you know
title that you are showing in your UI
and pull that information and show it in
the UI and that's how it works right
that's how like all the agent UIs that
you have chat JPT or Jiny or whatever is
that right and basically underneath this
this is how they do it okay Now let's
move forward and let's talk about um
something called structured output with
that like let me go ahead and clear this
let me clear this technically like now
what I want to do is that so user will
be saying like my name is uh um you know
John D and I'm 30 years old whatever is
that right now what I want to do is that
I want to extract this information
uh the user information right so
basically like I have defined my model
here. So when a when a user like when
when my agent respond back, it has to
respond back in this particular format.
Right? So ex now I'm saying like extract
the person information from the user's
text. So user will be providing this
kind of a text. Um so right my name is
whatever is that time you know how
oldever and then like I do this in this
particular city right. So now if you see
here usually like we will be passing the
user in input and like in the previous
like file we showed you like how do we
use the thread information. Now we will
introduce one more. So this is called
response format. When you pass the
response format
u then the you know agent will will know
that hey like I need to respond back to
the user but like when you respond back
to the user I have to follow this
particular format right. So now with
that like let me go and run this
particular file. So this is 19.
Okay. Now let me run this file. So this
is the user input. Now let's say like
how exactly the agent it's responding.
So the agent is responding name is this,
age is this, occupation is this, city is
this. So now what I'm saying is that you
know you really don't have to have the
uh you know very paragraph kind of a
response from the agent rather like you
can very well control the response
format by defining your uh data format
here right so like likewise like if you
see here this is the data format that
should exactly match the age occupation
city everything should match exactly
what happens in in keys it doesn't have
the information it is going to be empty
right but then like it shows the way for
us to extract the information in the
format that I am interested in that can
be very depending let's say like how do
we extract the user personal information
right for instance let's say like I'm
saying like my name is Karthikumar and I
live in Toronto and I like to play
cricket and I have you know a specific
kind of a car right so these are all the
information the agent can capture and uh
keep it so that uh in the future future
when you want to ask something here like
I am looking for a paint for my car now
you really don't have to specify which
car you are talking about because like
the agent should have all your
information right so we will extract all
this information and store it into the
profile so in this time around I don't
want to define the data model here
rather like I want to say like any
personal information any capture and
store it into your profile file
for let's see like how exactly this is
going to work here. So now let me go
ahead and minimize this. So like we will
be using something called AI memory
extractor. It's a it's a pretty simple
Python file implementation right. So
when a program starts it try to see if
there is any existing file. If there is
a file then it will load that
information. Basically like this file
will have all your profile information
pretty similar to this thread.json file.
So we'll create right now what we'll do
is that whenever user send a message we
will be calling something called
invoking. So that would be part of this
class a memory extractor. So that class
will get called that will load the
profile information and that information
will be passed to the agent. And now the
agent will have your query as well as
your profile information based on which
it will respond back after the uh you
know after the we receive the response
from the llm. Now what we'll do is that
we will call something called invoked
method that is again part of the same
class. So what it will do is that it
will extract the personal information
and like it will store that information
into the JSON file. So that is the
process. So, so first we will load the
profile and pass the user query get the
response back to the user like once the
information is there then we will store
the any additional information we will
store it into the profile file right so
now let me go and see this file right so
this is how you implement a memory
extractor you will pass something called
context provider you will have these two
classes so invoking and invoked So the
difference is that invoking before you
pass it to the LLM invoked after you
pass like receive the information from
LLM again
uh again like this invoked method if you
see here internally it will make a call
to the uh LLM only. So ll you know it
will like whatever the information that
you have from the user query it will
pass it to the LLM saying that hey like
if you find any additional profile
information apart from like what I
already have extract that information
give it to me and like we will just
update the JSON file right go and run
this program.
So now let me go ahead and pass the
query here. So now I say my name is or
this whatever is that
[sighs and gasps]
I just go and send it to the agent. Now
it says now if you just come over here
there is a file created with all this
information right. So I didn't say like
what exactly you have to extract right
but then like I leave it up to the LLM
to identify what are all the information
that you know you consider the LLM
consider for the profile right I store
all this information so now let me go
and uh see I like to play what is that
right also
next time I see this.
So now let me go and uh ask. Now the
agent should have enough information.
Now if I just come over here, it
captures all this information.
So now let me go ahead and u what is the
weather in my
place right? Because I did not say
anything. It should pull up the
information from the profile. It says
that um Toronto something about Toronto
right. Now how you create a profile user
profile and you know store it and like
that will be used in the subsequent
from the user. Right? We understood what
is this thread and how do we better use
this thread. Right? Coming videos we
will discuss about some of the most
advanced concepts like middleware
observability. How do we use the MCP?
Thank you for watching this video.